Cynthia Eddy Frontend Developer

cynthiaeddynyc@gmail.com | 212.604.0450 | New York, NY | cynthiaeddy.netlify.app | github.com/cynthiaeddy | linkedin.com/in/cynthiaeddy

PROJECTS

James Oseland's World Food, a React app. GITHUB | DEMO

a website for James' new book series

- Incorporates Mailchimp for newsletter sign up.
- Renders two Carousels: one built from scratch, the other using a library.
- Displays a React frontend with CSS grid and flexbox, being responsive for mobile and desktop.

The Brooklyn Museum Project, a React app. GITHUB I DEMO

an app where you can search the museum's vast collection by the artist's name

- Chains 3 HTTP requests with axios to fetch data from the Brooklyn Museums API.
- Incorporates a Masonry Grid library to mimic how traditional museums display their art.
- Utilizes a Node/Express backend, and displays a React frontend with CSS grid and flexbox.

Adopt a Pet, a React app. GITHUB FRONTEND | GITHUB BACKEND | DEMO

an app for adopting/maintaining a virtual pet without the upkeep of a live one

- Persists each user's pets and experience to a Postgres database and provides a Rails API with JWT authorization.
- Displays a React frontend with Semantic UI React and CSS.
- Employs flexbox with a hamburger menu for mobile.

WORK HISTORY

Freelance Software Developer | August 2019-Present

- Collaborated with a team in a Scrum environment
- Submitted and reviewed PR's
- Created/modified apps with Client's input and approval

Freelance Digital, Print Art Director | June 2017-Present

- · Created new Brand identities
- Designed features within the Brand's constraints
- Continue to wear many hats as described in former experiences

Digital Art Director | September 2011-May 2017

Hearst | Women's Health | Prevention | People Magazine

SKILLS Adobe Digital Publishing Suite | Edge Animate | Photoshop PORTFOLIO cynthiaeddy.com/digital all located in New York, NY

- Reviewed content from print material and translated it using elements of the company's designated brand for user interaction on iPad/iPhone.
- Utilized Edge Animate and Photoshop to produce engaging interactive material for the reader.
- Redesigned iPad/iPhone editions to reflect current format to insure continued viewing by subscribers.
- Directed staff of 4, troubleshot design decisions to improve layout to best captivate and maintain readers' attention.

Art Director | April 1996-August 2011

Shape Magazine | Time Inc. Custom Publishing | TV Guide | Worth Magazine

SKILLS Indesign | k4 | Illustrator | Photoshop PORTFOLIO cynthiaeddy.com/print all located in New York NY

- Produced effective layouts, contributed to multiple redesigns under a high pressure environment; met deadlines on or ahead of schedule while continuously updating content based on feedback.
- Collaborated with editors to visualize their perception of stories; independently created end products.
- Conceptualized story content with illustrators to determine visual representation; hired talent based on whether subject matter and illustrator/photographer specialization were aligned.

Awarded for outstanding design by:

Print's Best Typography I PRINT'S Regional Design Annual I The Society of Publication Design

EDUCATION

Flatiron School, New York, NY | Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript immersive program General Assembly, New York, NY | Front-end web development

New School University , New York, NY I Non matriculated coursework on HTML, web design

New York University, New York, NY | Dreamweaver coursework

 $\textbf{Kansas University, Lawrence, KS} \ \ \textbf{I} \ \ \textbf{Bachelor of Fine Arts in Visual Communications}$



TECHNICAL SKILLS

Javascript
React.js
HTML/CSS
Node.js
Express.js
RESTful APIs
Ruby on Rails
MongoDB
Github, Heroku
Netlify, Adobe

Creative Cloud